# **Ben Howkins**

Northants, NN12 6EA

Telephone: 01327 350882 Mobile: 07957943810 LinkedIn URL: https://www.linkedin.com/in/ben-howkins-488295215/

E-mail: benhowkins03@hotmail.com

Web Developer qualified through Skillsoft in "Complete Web Design and Software Development" that has also passed the ISTQB Certified Testing Foundation level exam. Holds the ability to create clean code, as well as being able to maintain and reuse existing code. Well versed in coding languages such as HTML, CSS and JavaScript. Possesses strong communication, problem-solving and time management skills from my 16+ years in Customer Service. Actively looking for an opportunity as a **Junior Web Developer** to build on and improve my current skills, whilst also learning new ones and creating my future in Web Development.

#### Skills

- Strong web design skills using HTML, CSS and JavaScript
- Understanding of Fundamental test methods including Blackbox, Whitebox and Dynamic testing
- Solid understanding of Automated testing
- Knowledge and understanding on the workings of Git and GitHub.
- Ability to create functional and interlinked webpages using HTML, CSS and JavaScript.

- Proficient understanding of the Project Lifecycle
- Effective Communication and Listening skills from 16+ years in customer service
- Excellent Time Management and planning skills from work to time deadlines as a Team Leader
- Problem-solving skills
- Strong Team working and Interpersonal Skills managing 10-15 Sales Consultant

## **Education and Training**

#### Complete Web Design and Software Development – Learning People

Modules: Learnt how to write HTML5, CSS, JavaScript and Python. As well as the concepts and workings of Bootstraps, UI/UX Design and Development, SQL and Git/GitHub

**Certified Testing Foundation Level-** International Software Testing Qualification Board:

**AAT Level 2, 2019** 

Level 3 in Admin and Secretarial Skills, 2017

First Aid at Work through Midcounties Co-Operative

#### **Coding Milestone Projects**

Project Title 1: Ice Hockey (HTML, CSS)

**Description:** A static website about the sport of Ice Hockey aimed to give information to newcomers. It outlines some information and the history of the sport, a description of the rules and information on the NHL and the team

that compete in it.

Languages used: HTML, CSS

**GitHub link:** https://github.com/BenHowkins/html-css-project **Deployed Project:** https://benhowkins.github.io/html-css-project/

Project Title 2: Stick, Net, Puck (JavaScript)

**Description:** A JavaScript game based along the same lines as Rock, Paper, Scissor but instead using an Ice Hockey Stick, Net and Puck as the available options. You compete against the computer to be the first to score 5 goals and win the game.

Languages used: HTML, CSS, JavaScript

**GitHub link:** https://github.com/BenHowkins/JavaScript\_Project **Deployed Project:** https://benhowkins.github.io/JavaScript\_Project/

Project Title 3: Tactical Sea Combat (Python)

Description: A Battleships style game where the player must find the enemy ship within a set number of turns by

guessing its location using coordinated guesses

Languages used: Python

GitHub link: https://github.com/BenHowkins/python\_project

**Deployed Project:** https://tactical-sea-combat-project.herokuapp.com/

Project Title 4: Otaku Blog

**Description:** A Django made blog where people can communicate about movies, video games and anime shows. Visitors can create accounts as well as comment on and like posts and have the ability to update and delete any comments they make.

Languages/ Skills to be used: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Django, jQuery, Bootstrap, Agile Development, Design Thinking

GitHub link: https://github.com/BenHowkins/otoku\_blog

**Deployed Project:** https://otaku-blog-3f79f19c74fc.herokuapp.com/

Project Title 5: Nerd Box

**Description:** A Django made e-commerce store where customers can buy themed goodie boxes based around movies, video games and anime shows. Visitors can create accounts so they can save their details such as name and address for future use as well as being able to see past transactions they have made.

Languages/ Skills to be used: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Django, jQuery, Bootstrap, Stripe, Agile Development, Design

Thinking

GitHub link: https://github.com/BenHowkins/nerd\_box\_pp5

Deployed Project: https://nerd-box-cc697c19580a.herokuapp.com/

Work Experience

#### **Customer Sales/ Team Leader**

2005-Present

Somerfield/ Midcounties Co-Op

Key Achievement: Myself and the store manager kept the store running efficiently and productively for a period of 10 days when three of the five management staff were absent due to illness.

### Responsibilities:

- Managed a team of 10-15 Sales Executives over 16+ years, including during Covid-19 pandemic whilst maintaining high sales and staff retention
- Handling immediately any complaints that are directed towards Team performance
- Maintaining a high work standard and ethic in the store resulting in two 'Employee of The Month' awards
- High quality and quantity of communication and people skill which can vary due to the environment and situation

# **Further Education and Training**

Northampton College Booth Lane 2007-2009:

• BTEC National Certificate in Health Studies - Distinction /Merit Grade

Sponne School, Towcester 2006-2007:

- AS in Health and Social Care
- AS in Psychology

Sponne School, Towcester 2004 -2006:

• 8 GCSE's Grade A-C including English, Math and Sciences

#### Interests and Activities

• Keen interest in increasing their knowledge in particular languages, both coding like **React, C#** and **Ruby** or verbal like **German** and **Japanese.** 

- Avid Ice hockey fan and a season ticket holder at my local club Milton Keynes Lightning.
- A very big fan of video games that owns all the latest consoles and currently researching components needed to build a gaming PC.
- A real fondness for movies, going at least once a week and currently a member with both Cineworld and local independent cinema.
- Love of food, going out to eat at restaurants of different cuisines or cooking meals at home at every opportunity.